PROFILE

Nicklas is a passionate and driven software developer with 4 years of professional experience. Alongside his development career he also built and developed a startup in the e-commerce sphere. Currently he is helping both enterprises and startups with in realizing both their and their customers projects in web and app development. Nicklas have always had his focus set on meeting customer needs and putting the task at hand front and center. He prefers working closely with this clients and thrives in environments where creativity and inovation is expected.



NICKLAS HERRERA HANSSON

Freelance Full Stack Software Developer

CONTACT



+46(0)73 82 28 448



nicklas@miratodev.com



Stockholm / Alicante

EDUCATION

Sep 2019 - Dec 2020

Bachelor of Computer Science

Linnaeus University, Kalmar

Jan 2015 - Present

Self Teaching

Various web sources

Jan 2019 - March 2019

Web Development

CodeCademy.com

Nov 2018 - Jan 2019

Data Science

CodeCademy.com

Sep 2018 - Nov 2018

Computer Science

CodeCademy.com

SKILLS

- Javascript & NodeJS
- React, NextJS & React Native
- Vue, Nuxt
- Firebase, GraphQL, SQL, MongoDB
- Express.js, Nginx
- Docker, Kubernetes, GCP

WORK EXPERIENCE

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

Frontend Developer

Carismar AB (CC Projects)

- Working closely with the Project Leader to estimate projects that their clients asked for.
- Worked on a number of web shops including names as Bubbleroom.se, Zoovillage.com,
 Motostar.se, Harlequin.se, m.nu to name a few.
- Taking the lead in launching new markets for existing web
- Handled customer contact on projects.
- Further developing the in-house Vue/Nuxt-based product which is Carismars freshly built storefront.
- Built custom frontend components and developed new site behavior.
- Handling deployment for said websites in Azure DevOps.

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

Full stack developer

Glossa (Freelance)

- Worked on a product that was built to help stroke patients regain their communication skills.
- Developed new functionality and further developed existing functions.
- Updated the tech stack to be compatible with modern devices.
- Built a CI/CD workflow for the Mobile app to achieve a better developing experience and save a lot of time in development.
- Implemented new behavior in the mobile app to further expand the number of exercises available for the users.

Feb 2022 - May 2022

Solutions architect / Full stack developer

Umain AB (Freelance)

- Developed application architecture strategy to specifically align with employer business goals.
- Participated in weekly meetings with client to discuss project direction and milestone achievement.
- Broke down technical ideas and issues into non-technical terms for business executives.

CONTACT



+46(0)73 82 28 448



nicklas@miratodev.com



Stockholm / Alicante

EXPERTISE

- Master Googler
- Adobe xD, Figma
- Adobe Photoshop
- Postman
- Git
- VS Code

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Customized in-development software to clients' current environments, designing applications to span multiple systems.
- Implemented new frontend with accompanying authorization system taking into account the plans for future SaaS sales.
- Worked with developers and engineers to realize technological solutions.

Apr 2021 - Feb 2022

Full stack developer / DevOps Engineer

Ed's Städfirma (Freelance)

- Designing and Developing the future main digital work tool for a large cleaning company in Stockholm.
- Managing front-end and back-end development from requirements documents to finished product.
- Using modern web framework Next.js which is based on React.
- With the help of JWT and Rest-api I am leveraging the clients current WordPress installation for managing authentication and content delivery.
- I also had to find a solution for bringing their current database (FileMaker) into the project
 making a seamless product whether viewing static content from WordPress or
 dynamically changing content in the database.

Apr 2019 - Present

Founder, CEO & Full-Stack Developer

Gladli AB

- Created business requirements and technical and quality assurance specifications.
- Developed use cases in accordance with requirements and built back-end and front-end that met the stakeholder's expectations.
- Created a multi-platform SaaS (Web, iOS, Android) to solve a problem experienced by small and medium business owners.
- Hired and lead new key members to ensure forecasted objectives were met and overall desired outcomes achieved.
- Recruited several pilot customers and negotiated mutually beneficial co- operations with other business and services.

2013 - 2020

IT-technician

Royal Library of Sweden

 Worked alongside a team of IT-technicians and independently overseeing network operations and Active Directory management.

2008 - 2011

1st Line Support Agent

Bredbandsbolaget

CONTACT



+46(0)73 82 28 448



nicklas@miratodev.com



Stockholm / Alicante

SIDE PROJECTS

Feb 2021 - Aug 2021

Small Full stack service

I am building a full stack service aiming to help people in Stockholm to find 1st hand lease contracts for apartments. This project is built with the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js) where I am also implementing Stripe subscriptions to make the service available for the consumers.

Apr 2019 - Sep 2019

Full stack scheduling tool

I spent around 5-6 months building the beginning of a full stack web application that was going to be a scheduling tool for a cleaning company. I built the project with React.js as the frontend and Express.js and MySQL as the backend. The project was never completed because of time constraints.

Dec 2018 - Mar 2019

Financial analysis tool

I spent 3-4 months building a tool to analyze cryptocurrency financial data from exchanges to help with buy/sell signals. This was built with Python using a library called CCXT, Matplotlib, Pandas and a few other parts. I used SQLite as a store of data for analysis.